TP-LINK PRIVACY POLICY
----------------------

Last Updated: Nov, 24 2022

TP-Link Corporation Limited (“TP-Link,” “we” “us,” or “our”), takes your privacy seriously. We want you to understand what information we collect, and how we use and share it. That’s why we encourage reading our Privacy Policy. This helps your use TP-Link Products and Services in a way that’s right for you. Some Products and Services of TP-Link can be used together or in ways that integrate with products and services from third parties. Using third-party products and services may allow the third party to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party products and services, and we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every third-party product and service you use.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it explains how we collect information, how we use the information we collect, and with whom we disclose such information. By using or accessing our Products and Services in any matter, you accept and consent to the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy incorporates herein the Terms of Use; both statements should be read in conjunction with each other. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Your continued engagement with our Products and Services after such revisions indicates that you accept and consent to them, so please check the Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

Supplemental data protection information for specific countries and/or regions where TP-Link is active is also available. For further information regarding data protection in a specific country and/or region, please refer to the privacy policy tailored for that specific country and/or region via [https://www.tp-link.com/en/choose-your-location/](https://www.tp-link.com/en/choose-your-location/). You may consult the respective privacy policy for your residing country/region for your data protection.

**What Products and Services does this policy cover?**

(1) TP-Link branded hardware, firmware, and software products (“Products”);

(2) website(s) that may be accessed at https://www.tp-link.com, https://www.kasasmart.com, and https://www.vigi.com (“Sites”);

(3) services, including on and through the Products, and technical support and services accessible through the Site(s) (“Web Apps”);

(4) software that may be downloaded to your smartphone or tablet to access services (“Mobile Apps”); 

(5) subscription services, including services that can be accessed using Web Apps and Mobile Apps (“Subscription Services”). The term “Services” means the Sites, Web Apps, Mobile Apps, and Subscription Services, which may be used in conjunction with Products and in other ways provided by TP-Link.

### **1\. YOUR** **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We collect and use different types of data from and about you, including:

1.1 Personal Information You Provide to Us:

You provide information to us when you：

* search for products or services on our website；
* place order in our stores;
* download, stream, view, or use content on a device (camera usually), or through a service or application on a device;
* provide information in Your Account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address or mobile number when you register and use our Products and Services) or Your Profile;
* configure your settings on, provide data access permissions for, or interact with a TP-Link device or service;
* communicate with us by phone, e-mail, livechat, or otherwise;
* complete a questionnaire, a contest entry form, or beta testing application;
* upload or stream images, videos, or other files to the cloud Services;
* post new topics on the TP-Link Community forum.

As a result of those actions, you might supply us with information such as:

* identifying information such as your name, address, and phone numbers;
* payment information;
* your location information;
* people, addresses, and phone numbers listed in your Addresses;
* email address;
* content of livechats, posts, and emails to us;
* personal description and photograph in Your Profile;
* images and videos collected by cameras or stored in connection with subscribed cloud services;
* device log files and configurations, including Wi-Fi credentials, if you choose to automatically synchronize them with your other devices or third-party accounts.

1.2 Automatic Information

We automatically collect information about you when you access or use our Products and Services. For example, when you connect hardware devices or third-party services to your account, those hardware devices may report usage information to the Services, and the Services may read, process, and store this information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Such information is usually associated with the usage of the particular hardware device or third-party service, such as when a motion sensor senses motion. The Services will receive information about the device activation, as well as the information that you have chosen to associate with the Product or Service such as device name, group name, and location name. The type of the Product or Service from which information is received will change the types and quantities of information that is received.

We also collect the information about how you interact with our Site and Services, which may include the pages accessed and links clicked on our site, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, MAC address, access times, location, mobile device information, operating system, browser type, certain demographic information, application information, and other information associated with how you interact with the Site and Services. We will collect a device’s browser history and access time when the device is under the control of the Parental Controls feature, such as the Parental Controls feature on Deco Products, in order to better monitor the device which is under control. We will record and analyze a device's attempted URL connections and block access to malicious websites (such as phishing / fraud / fake websites) only when the device has the Real-Time Protection feature enabled. Data will no longer be collected after you turn off this feature.

1.3 Information from Other Sources

We may receive data from other sources including, but not limited to, third-party service providers which you have integrated into our Products and Services and/or voluntarily have provided with data and/or from our authorized partners, or others that we use to fulfill our obligations to you as a customer. You should carefully and diligently review the terms and conditions and privacy policies of those third-party products and services, and we will consider your decision to use those third-party products and services with our Products and Services to be a representation to us that you have consented to the third parties' terms and practices.

### **2\.** **HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

We use your personal information to operate, provide, develop, and improve the products and services that we offer our products. These purposes include:

* Purchase and delivery of products and services. We use your personal information to take and handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, and communicate with you about orders, products and services, and promotional offers.
* Provide, troubleshoot, and improve our Products and Services. We use your personal information to provide functionality, analyze performance, fix errors, and improve the usability and effectiveness of our Products and Services.
* Recommendations and personalization. We use your personal information to recommend features, products, and services that might be of interest to you, identify your preferences, and personalize your experience with our Products and Services.
* Provide voice, image, and camera services. When you use our voice, image, and camera services, we use your voice input, images, videos, and other personal information to respond to your requests, provide the requested service to you, and improve our services.
* Comply with legal obligations. In certain cases, we collect and use your personal information to comply with applicable laws. For instance, we collect from Partner Program users information regarding taxpayer identification number and bank account information for tax purposes.
* Communicate with you. We use your personal information to communicate with you in relation to our Products and Services via different channels (e.g., by phone, email, livechat).
* Marketing. We use your personal information to display interest-based ads for features, products, and services that might be of interest to you. We do not use information that personally identifies you to display interest-based ads.
* Fraud Prevention and Credit Risks. We use personal information to prevent and detect fraud and abuse in order to protect the security of our customers, TP-Link, and others.

We will only process your personal data for the purposes of providing Products and Services in compliance with applicable laws, as may be amended from time to time.

### **3\. WHAT ABOUT COOKIES AND OTHER IDENTIFIERS?**

Cookies are small pieces of text used to store information on web browsers. Cookies are used to store and receive identifiers and other information on computers, phones, and other devices. Other technologies, including data that we store on your web browser or device, identifiers associated with your device and other software, are used for similar purposes. In this policy, we refer to all of these technologies as “cookies”.

We use cookies to distinguish you from other users. This helps us deliver a better and more personalized service when you use our Products and Services. It also allows us to improve our Products and Services by enabling us to:

* estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
* store your preferences so we may customize our Products and Services according to your individual interests;
* speed up your searches;
* recognize you when you return;
* keep your account, data, and our Products and Services safe and secure;
* promote the products or services to you that you may be interested in; and
* measure the performance of cooperating third-party sellers.

You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting, certain parts of our Website may become inaccessible and certain features may not work correctly. Unless you adjust your browser settings to refuse cookies, our system will issue them.

### **4\.** **HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION**

We may share your personal information internally and externally with suppliers, advisors, or Partners for our legitimate business purposes, and only on a need-to-know basis. When sharing personal information, we implement appropriate checks and controls to confirm that the information can be shared in accordance with applicable laws. Here’s more detail about who we may share your information with and in what kinds of situations:

(1) _With Our Authorized Partners_: We may share your information with our authorized partners. We share information with our authorized partners to

* promote safety, security, and integrity and comply with applicable laws;
* personalize offers, ads, and other sponsored or commercial content;
* develop and provide features and integrations;
* understand how customers use and interact with our Products and Services.

(2) _Service Providers_: To assist in our business operations and better provide Products and Services (e.g., for software maintenance services, advertising serving technologies, e-mail services, delivery services, database management services, web analytics, and other services), we may share your information with such service provider.

(3) _Other Entities with Your Consent_: You may choose to integrate certain third-party services with our Services. By doing so, you authorize us to transmit your personal information to third parties when you choose to integrate their services with our Services. Information collected by such third-party services is subject to their own terms and policies, all of which you should carefully and diligently review.

(4) _Marketing_: We may aggregate anonymized user information and provide it to our third-party marketing service providers only for our promotional and/or marketing practices.

(5) _Change of Control_: We may be required to share your information as part of a merger, acquisition, asset sale, asset purchase, financing, bankruptcy, or other change of control.

(6) _Responding to Legal Requests_: We may share information where we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with an applicable law or legal process or (b) respond to actual or potential complaints or legal claims, like search warrants, court orders, production orders, or subpoenas. These requests come from third parties such as civil litigants, law enforcement, and other government authorities. Or (c) where otherwise necessary to protect our rights, interests, and/or property (including, without limitation, to enforce our agreements), or the rights, interests, and/or property of our agents, independent contractors, customers, and others.

### **5\.** **SECURITY**

We have implemented measures, including encryption and TLS technology, designed to secure your personal data from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. In addition, we restrict the number of staff in charge with access to your personal data to the minimum level and frequently conduct training and education so that they comply with the confidentiality obligations with respect to your personal data.

Your account’s privacy and security are protected by your password. In order to prevent unauthorized access to your account and personal data, you should select a strong password and protect it by limiting access to your computer, device, browser, or application and by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. If you use a third-party service to sign into your account, you should protect that account accordingly as well.

While we strive to always protect the privacy of your account and personal data in our records, we cannot always guarantee it will be completely secure. The security of your personal data may be compromised by unauthorized entry, unauthorized use, hardware failure, software failure, and other factors at any time.

Here are some best practices to protect your TP-Link ID account:

* **Use complex passwords (a mixture of upper and lower letters, numbers, and symbols) when signing up.**
* **Use a unique password different from other website accounts to avoid being involved in their accidental data breaches.**
* **Change your passwords regularly.**
* **Use 2 Factor Authentication (2FA) if possible.**

### **6\. HOW WE STORE AND PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION**

Your information will be transferred or transmitted to, or stored and processed in the following circumstances in accordance with the purposes stated within this Privacy Policy:

* Places we have infrastructure or data centers, including the United States, Ireland, and Singapore, among other Countries where TP-Link Products and Services are available. Typically, the primary storage region is the region that is closest to the customer’s region, often with backups to data centers in another region. The storage location(s) are chosen in order to operate efficiently, to improve performance, and to create redundancies in order to protect the data in the event of an outage or other problem.
* Other countries where our Partners, vendors, service providers and third parties are located outside of the country where you live, for purposes as described in this Privacy Policy.

These countries may have different privacy standards that differ from where you are. Please note that data processed in another country may be subject to different laws and may be accessible to government, judicial, law enforcement, and regulatory agencies in those countries. However, we will take appropriate measures to guarantee an adequate level of data protection even if your personal data are transferred to these countries.

### **7\.** **THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

The Services may include links to third-party websites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. Your usage of any such websites is governed by the privacy policies of those websites and not this Privacy Policy. You should carefully review the privacy policy of any website you visit. We will consider your decision to use those third-party products and services with our Products and Services to be a representation to us that you have consented to the third parties' terms and practices.

### **8\.** **YOUR CHOICES**

We offer you a variety of tools to view, manage, download, and delete your information below. You can also manage your information by visiting the settings of the Products you use. You may also have other privacy rights under applicable laws. To exercise your rights, visit your setting.. For example, you can:

* Update your account information and settings at any time by accessing your Mobile Apps, Subscription Services, or Web Apps.
* Control how and when you want to receive notifications from us in the Mobile Apps.
* Opt-out of our email service by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of our emails.
* Not use features and Services that require you to provide your information and data, such as our community or video storage.
* Request data deletion at [https://account-delete.tplinkcloud.com/](https://account-delete.tplinkcloud.com/ "https://account-delete.tplinkcloud.com/").
* You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies.

You may also send us an email at [privacy@tp-link.com](mailto:privacy@tp-link.com) to request access to, correct, or delete personal data that you have provided to us. However, with respect to the administrative emails for your registered account (e.g., emails about your transactions, policy changes, forgotten password, and confirmation emails), we cannot delete them except by also deleting your user account. We may not accommodate a request to change or delete information if we believe the change or deletion would violate any law or legal requirement or negatively impact the information's accuracy.

### **9\.** **CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Our Products and Services are not directed to, or intended for, children as defined by local legal requirements, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children. If you believe that we have any such information, please notify us immediately using the contact information provided in Section 11 and we will delete the information as quickly as possible.

### **10\. CALIFORNIA CONSUMER PRIVACY ACT**

Click [here](https://www.tp-link.com/us/about-us/privacy/your-california-privacy-rights/) to read additional disclosures required under the California Consumer Privacy Act.

### **11\.** **UPDATES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and we may notify you by updating the Privacy Policy’s effective date above. If there are material changes, we will place a prominent notice on this website. We encourage all users to occasionally refer to this Privacy Policy so that they can remain aware of our current practices. If you do not agree with the terms of the updated Privacy Policy, you must stop using the Products/Services. You continued use of the Products/Service after any Privacy Policy changes means that you agree to the updated Privacy Policy.

### **12\.** **CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or need further assistance, please email us at  [privacy@tp-link.com](mailto:privacy@tp-link.com)

TP-Link Corporation Limited

Room 901,9/F.，New East Ocean Centre, 9 Science Museum Road, Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon, Hong Kong
